Guide to the Gerald Stern Papers, 1920s-2012 SC.2007.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Poetry and Other Works, 1940-2012; I.
  - Paradise Poems, 1984; 7.
    This subseries includes materials related to Paradise Poems, published in 1984 by Random House. Materials include notes and drafts for individual poems, organized according to the order they appear in the book. Following the individual poems are notebooks, correspondence with publishers, and proofs and galleys that include Stern's notes and corrections.
    - Orange Roses (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Later Today (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Rhododendron (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Picking the Roses (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - In Memory of W. H. Auden (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Clay Dog (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Steve Dunn's Spider (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Romania, Romania (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - It's Nice to Think of Tears (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Souls from Emerson (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Song (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Weeping and Waiting (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Hidden Justice (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Christmas Sticks (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Same Moon Above Us (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Leaving Another Kingdom (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Near Perigord (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - For Song (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - My Swallows (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Berkeley (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - The Dancing (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Moscow (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - May 15 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Bee Balm (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Vivaldi Years (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Dubuque Street, and, Saying the First Words (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Huzza! (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Night Again (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Today a Leaf (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - The New Moses (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Singing (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - The Seine at Night (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - At Jane's (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - John's Mysteries (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Soap (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - I Pity the Wind (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - 82/83 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Romance (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Villa-Lobos (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - The Nettle Tree (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Sycamore (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Baja (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Of Blessed Name (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Kissing Stieglitz Goodbye (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Two Trees (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - One Bird to Love Forever (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Fritz (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Three Skies (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Red Bird (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Adler (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - The Expulsion (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Ground Hog Lock (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - July 2, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - The Dogs (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Notebooks (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Translations (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Reviews (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Correspondence with Random House (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Typescript with handwritten notes (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Bound galley proof with notes (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Galley proof (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Setting copy (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Master set, first pass (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Master set, second pass (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - 1st Vintage Press edition galley (2 copies) (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Galley as revised to April 26, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Galley as revised to May 25, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Unbound copy of book (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Lovesick, 1987; 8.
    This subseries contains materials related to Stern's Lovesick, published in 1987 by Harpercollins and includes notes and drafts for individual poems, organized according to the order they appear in the publication. Following individual poems are notebooks, reviews, correspondence with publishers, and galleys and proofs that include Stern's notes and corrections.
    - Nobody Else Living (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Lovesick (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - All I Have Are the Tracks (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - I do a Piece From Greece (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - I Hate My Moaning (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - This Was a Wonderful Night (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - I Sometimes Think of the Lamb (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Stopping Schubert (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - I am in a Window (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bela (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - A Song for the Romeos (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Tashlikh (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Pussy Willow (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Richard Strauss, My Hero (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - My First Kinglet (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - I Slept Like That (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lillian Harvey (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - There I was One Day (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - One Animal's Life (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Silver Hand (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Washington Square (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Arranging a Thorn (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - The Dog (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Shaking Myself and Sighing (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - A Pair of Hands (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Bob Summers' Body (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - It Was in Houston (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Neither English nor Spanish (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - I am in Love (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - My Favorite Demon (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Another Insane Devotion (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - The Blink of an Eye (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Making The Light Come (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - It was a Rising (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Hobbes (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Grapefruit (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - A Garden (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - No Longer Terror (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Nobody Else Alive (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Knowledge Forwards and Backwards (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Saturday Afternoon (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Two Moons (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Lyric (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - My Favorite Farewell (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - For Once (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Stolen Face (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Steps (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Notebooks (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Translations (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Reviews (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Publicity and advertisement (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Typescript with notes (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Copy edited manuscript (original and photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Galley proof with notes (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Galleys in page form, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Bound uncorrected proof (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Camera copy (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Cover proofs (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Leaving Another Kingdom, 1990; 9.
    Leaving Another Kingdom, published in 1990 by Harpercollins was a collection of previously published poems. The subseries includes only a typescript, proof, and a galley.
    - Typescript (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Bound uncorrected proof (2 copies) (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - Galleys with cover (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Bread Without Sugar, 1992; 10.
    This suberies includes materials related to Stern's 1993 collection of poetry, Bread Without Sugar, published by W.W. Norton and Co. The poem "Bread Without Sugar," was first published in 1991 by Sutton Hoo Press. Sutton Hoo was a fine press publisher founded in Iowa City in 1989. The publication of his long poem would be their first.
    The subseries includes notes and drafts of individual poems, orgainzed according the order they appear in the book, follwed by reviews, correspondence with publishers,typescripts, proofs, and galleys--many of which include Stern's notes and corrections.
    - Sylvia (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Three Hearts (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - My Death for Now (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - One Day an Arbor Vitae (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Brain of My Heart (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Founder (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The First Lewd Offering (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nice Mountain (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Love is the Opposite (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - The Age of Strolling (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Sending Back the Gloom (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - One Gift (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - First Day of Spring (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - R for Rosemary (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - How Would it Be? (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Saving My Skin from Burning (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Shouting (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - The Eyes Are Always Brown (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - A Song for Kenneth Burke (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Aspiring to Music (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Grinnell, Iowa (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Ukrainian (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Coleman Valley Road (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - What It Is Like (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Two Daws (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Her Right Eye Catches the Lavendar (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - His Song of the Green Willow (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Those Things, and, If the Lark Had Thorns (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - The Smell of Death (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Red with Pink (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Someone Will Do It for Me (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - I Would Call It Derangement (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - The Thought of Heaven (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Bread Without Sugar (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Notes (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Reviews and Translations (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence with The Georgia Review (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence with W.W. Norton & Company, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Typescript (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Bound uncorrect proof (2 copies) (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Unbound manuscript with printing notes (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Master pages proof (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Master galleys (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Reproduction duplicates (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Odd Mercy, 1995; 11.
    Stern's ninth collection of poetry, Odd Mercy, published in 1995 by W.W. Norton included 22 poems.
    The subseries includes notes and drafts of individual poem, organized according to the order they appear in the book, followed by notebooks, reviews, correspondence with publishers, and a typescript, proof, and galley which include Stern's notes and corrections.
    - Birthday (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Odd Mercy (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Blue (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bitter Thoughts (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Ducks Are for Our Happiness (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Diary (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Mimi (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Hinglish (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Finding the Bush (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Blacker Than Ever (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Only Elegy (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Ida (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Small Sunflowers (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - The Jew and the Rooster Are One (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Fleur (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - St. Mark's (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Two Things (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Knowledge (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Sixteen Minutes (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Essay on Rime (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Hot Dog (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Notebooks (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Reviews (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence with W.W. Norton & Company, Inc. (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Typescript with notes (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Bound uncorrected proof (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Galley (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - This Time: New and Selected Poems, 1998; 12.
    National Book Award winner, This Time, was published in 1998 and included selections from his previous seven books of poetry and 14 new poems. The subseries mostly includes drafts of the new poems and various publication materials, like proofs, as well as materials realted the publication's National Book Award for Poetry.
    - December 1, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Both of Them Were Sixty-Five (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Memoirs (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Lilacs for Ginsberg (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Notes (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - List of Reviewers (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Reviews (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Publicity (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Typescript (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Proof (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Galleys (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - 1998 National Book Award for Poetry (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Underground Dancing, 1999; 13.
    This subseries includes one galley for the Polish translation of Stern's poem Underground Dancing, translated by Adam Szyper and published in 1999.
    - Underground Dancing (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Last Blue, 2000; 14.
    This subseries includes materials related to Last Blue, published in 2001 by W.W. Norton and Co., and includes notes and drafts for individual poems, according to the order they appear in the book. This is followed by various typescripts, proofs, and galleys, organized according to the publishing process, and include Stern's notes and corrections.
    New materials were added to the subseries in 2015 and include additional typescripts and a galley.
    - Once of the Smallest (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Pluma (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Against The Crusades (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Whatever Paris Meant (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Someone to Watch Over Me (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Wailing (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - An Explanation (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Domestic (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Light (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - The Sorrows (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Progress and Poverty (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Pennsylvania Bio (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - A Rose Between The Sheets (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Swifts (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - About Women (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Some Brown (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Forsythia (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - The Music (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Night (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Drowning on the Pamet River (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Mexican (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Paris (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - March 27 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - The Dove's Neck (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Sleep (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - The Joke (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Snowdrop (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - December '98 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Last Blue (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Vision and What It Was (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Kingdom (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Notes (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Notebooks (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Notebooks (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Reviews and Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Typescript with notes (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Typescript with notes (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Bound uncorrected proof (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Master galleys, first pass (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Master galleys, second pass (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Master galleys, third Pass (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - 2015 Addition
      - Early typescript with notes (Box 9, Folder 42-43)
      - Typescript with early changes (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - Typescript, marked up by Norton (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - Copyedited galley (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - Foul matter from Norton (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - American Sonnets, 2002; 15.
    This subseries includes materials related to American Sonnets, published in 2003 by W.W. Norton and Co., and includes notes and drafts for individual poems, according to the order they appear in the book. This is followed by notebooks, correspondence with pubishers, and various proofs and galleys, organized according to the publishing process, and that include Stern's notes and corrections.
    - Winter Thirst (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - How a Word Can Breathe, and, September, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - June (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Once (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - For the Bee (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Alone (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - My Tenderness (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - You (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Flexible Flyer (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Beechview (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - The Inkspots (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Peaches (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Exordium and Terminus (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Grass and Water (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - In Time (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Sink (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Mimi (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - All I Did for Him (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Places You Wouldn't Believe (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Pag (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Hydrangea (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Crosshatching (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Spider (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Dandelions (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Hats (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - String Bean (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Savel Kliatchko (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Irishry (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Grand Hotel (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Sam and Morris (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Burning (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Studebaker (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Standing Up (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Cost (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Still Burning (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Samaritans (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Roses (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Letters (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - The Hammer (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Hearts (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Ted Rosenberg (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Slash of Red (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Egg, and, Justice (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Notes (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Notebooks (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Reviews (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Typescript (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - Corrected manuscript (2 copies) (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Proofs, author's set (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - Proofs, master set (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Galleys (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - What I Can't Bear Losing, 2004; 16.
    This subseries includes materials related to Stern's collection of personal essays, What I Can't Bear Losing, published in 2004 by W.W. Norton and Co., and includes notes and drafts for individual essays, organized according to the order they appear in the book. This is followed by notebooks, correspondence, and typescripts, organized according to the publishing process, and that include Stern's notes and corrections.
    The book was republished in 2009 with the addition of seven new essays. Materials related to the 2009 edition are located under the subseries "2015 Addition."
    - Introduction (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Sunday (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - The Beacon (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - Remorse (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - First Rites (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Some Secrets (Box 10, Folder 58)
    - Hotel du Centre (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Vow of Silence (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - Paris Post (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Blessed (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - The Sabbath (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Bullet in My Neck (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Ginsberg and I (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Andy (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Caves (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - Charity (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - Tree of Life (Box 10, Folder 69)
    - The Ring (Box 10, Folder 70)
    - Salesman (Box 10, Folder 71)
    - A Day Without The Jews (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - What I Have to Defend, What I Can't Bear Losing (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - Notes (Box 10, Folder 74)
    - Notebooks (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - Notebooks (Box 10, Folder 76)
    - Reviews (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Publicity and advertisement (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence with W.W. Norton & Company, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - Typescript, part 1 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Typescript, part 2 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Copyright releases (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Everything Is Burning, 2005; 17.
    This subseries includes materials related to Stern's 15th book of poetry, Everything is Burning, published in 2006 by W.W. Norton and Co., and includes notes and drafts for individual poems, according to the order they appear in the book. This is followed by notebooks, various typescripts, proofs, and galleys, organized according to the publishing process, and include Stern's notes and corrections.
    - Strawberries (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Matins (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Google of Geese (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - The Perzola (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - The Cup (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Billy in the Next Room (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - E.P. I (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - E.P. II (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - E.P. III (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - I Was in Charge (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - The 18th Street Book Fair (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Berries of Death (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Albatross I (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Those Saucer that Were His Eyes (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Dead Bat (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Loving the Mirrors (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Never Went to Birdland (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Dr. Dunn (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Suzanne (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Tenderness (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - The Snow on the River (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - The Gulls (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Dog That I Am (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Sylvia (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Hemingway's House (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Just Say Goodbye to Mother (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - May 30 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Jack (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - May Frick Be Damned (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - The Trent Lott, The McNamara Blues (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Luck (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - The Tie (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Stern Country (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Bermuda (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Bolero (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Dumbbells (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Stern Country (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Gimbels (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Worms (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Trickle Down (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Richard (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Lilies (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Cheese (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Loyal Carp (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Golden Rule (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - City of God (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - The Taste of Ducklings (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - L'Chaim (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Cigars (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Good Boy (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Harold and I (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Shouldering (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Bejewels (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - My Sister's Funeral (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - The Red is Fuschia (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Anti-Goose (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - My First Shriek (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - One of My Legs (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Bio (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Moon (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Battle of the Bulge (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Mars (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Thought (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Desnos (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Plank Road (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Driven (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Twenty-Five Cents (Box 11, Folder 67)
    - Brain of Magellan (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Shepherd (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Corsets (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Sacco, Vanzetti (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Whoso (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - Homesick (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - The Law (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - She Was a Dove (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Notes (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Notebooks (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - Reviews (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence with W.W. Norton & Company, Inc. (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Copy of original typescript (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Revised typescript (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Master typescript (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Author's reference copy (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - First pass proofs (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Master galleys (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Master galleys, author's copy (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Not God After All, 2004; 18.
    Not God After All, published in 2004 by Autumn House Press, feature petite narratives accompanied by drawings by Sheba Sharrow. The subseries includes drafts, notes, reviews, publication information, and proofs.
    - Drafts of Introduction (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Drafts of A Fire I Understand (original title) (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Notes (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Reviews (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Autumn House Press (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Proofs (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - The Preacher, 2007; 19.
    Stern's long poem, The Preacher was published as part of the Quarternote Chapbook Series by Sarabade Books in 2007. The subseries mostly contains various typescripts with notes, correspondence, and proofs.
    - Preacher typescript 3, with notes (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Preacher typescript 4, with notes (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Preacher typescript with corrections made (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Preacher typescript with edits made (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Final Preacher typescript (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ecclesiastes as witness: a personal essay (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Vogelsang (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Untitled poem (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Notebooks (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - American Poetry Review (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Sarabande Books (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - First pass proofs (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Second pass proofs (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - 2015 Addition, 20.
    This subseries includes materials added to the collection in 2015 and is divided into sections for books published between 2008-2012.
    - Save the Last Dance, 2008